[{
        "questionId": 1,
        "question": "What is an activity in Android?",
        "options": {
            "A" : "Activity performs the actions on the screen",
            "B" : "Manage the Application content",
            "C" : "Screen UI",
            "D" : "None of the above"
        },
        "answer": "A"
    },
    {
        "questionId": 2,
        "question": " How to move services to foreground in android?",
        "options": {
            "A" : "Services always work in Foreground only",
            "B" : " No,We can't do this query",
            "C" : "Using startService(Intent intent)",
            "D" : "startForeground(int id, Notification notification)"
        },
        "answer": "D"
    },
    {
        "questionId": 3,
        "question": "How to stop the services in android?",
        "options": {
            "A" : "finish()",
            "B" : "system.exit()",
            "C" : "By Manually",
            "D" : "stopSelf() and stopService()"
        },
        "answer": "D"
    },
    {
        "questionId": 4,
        "question": "What is the difference between content values and cursor in android SQlite?",
        "options": {
            "A" : "Content values are key pair values, which are updated or inserted in the database",
            "B" : "Cursor is used to store the temporary result",
            "C" : "A & B",
            "D" : "Content values are used to share the data."
        },
        "answer": "C"
    },
    {
        "questionId": 5,
        "question": "What is JNI in android",
        "options": {
            "A" : "Java Network Interface",
            "B" : "Java Interface",
            "C" : "Image editable tool",
            "D" : "Java Native Interface"
        },
        "answer": "D"
    },
    {
    "questionId": 6,
    "question": "What are the debugging techniques available in Android",
        "options":{
        "A" : "DDMS",
        "B" :  "Breaking Point",
        "C" : "Memory Profiling",
        "D" : "All of the Above"
        },


    "answer": "D"
},
    {
        "questionId": 7,
        "question": "What is the package name of HTTP client in android?",
        "options": {
            "A" : "com.json",
            "B" : "org.apache.http.client",
            "C" : "com.android.JSON",
            "D" : "org.json"
        },
        "answer": "B"
    },
    {
    "questionId": 8,
    "question": "What is fragment lifecycle in Android?",
    "options": {
        "A" : "onReceive()",
        "B" : "onCreate()",
        "C" : "onAttach()->onCreate() −> onCreateView() −> onActivityCreated() −> onStart() −> onResume()",
        "D" : "None of the Above"
    },
    "answer": "C"
},{
    "questionId": 9,
    "question": "What is transient data in android?",
    "options": {
        "A" : "Permanent Data",
        "B" : "Secure Data",
        "C" : "Temporary Data",
        "D" : "Logical Data"
    },
    "answer": "D"
},{
    "questionId": 10,
    "question": "What is an interface in android?",
    "options": {
        "A" :"Interface acts as a bridge between class and the outside world.",
        "B" :"Interface is a class",
        "C" : "Interface is a layout file",
        "D" : "None of the above"
    },
    "answer": "D"
},{
    "questionId": 11,
    "question": "How to move services to foreground in android?",
    "options": {
        "A" : "Services always work in Foreground only",
        "B" : " startForeground(int id, Notification notification).",
        "C" : " No, we don't do this QUERY",
        "D" : "Using startService(Intent intent)"
    },
    "answer": "B"
},{
    "questionId": 12,
    "question": " How to stop the services in android ?",
    "options": {
        "A" : "stopSelf() and stopService()",
        "B" : "system.exit()",
        "C" : "finish()",
        "D" : "By Manually"
    },
    "answer": "A"
},{
    "questionId": 13,
    "question": "___________ allows you to create large and complex layouts with a flat view hierarchy",
    "options": {
        "A" : "Constraint Layout",
        "B" : "Grid Layout",
        "C" : "Recycler View",
        "D" : "Relative layout"
    },
    "answer": "A"
},
    {
    "questionId": 14,
        "question": "Android application can be built by using following language.",
        "options": {
            "A" : "Java",
            "B" : "Kotlin",
            "C" : "Both A & B",
            "D" : "None of the above"
        },
        "answer": "C"
    },
    {
    "questionId": 15,
        "question": "Android is an operating system based on ________ with a Java programming interface for mobile devices such as Smartphone (Touch Screen Devices who supports Android OS) as well for Tablets too.",
        "options": {
            "A" : "Linux",
            "B" : "Windows",
            "C" : "Unix",
            "D" : "Linux Kernel"
        },
        "answer": "D"
    },
    {
    "questionId": 16,
        "question": "An ____________  is basically a message that is passed between components ",
        "options": {
            "A" : "Activity",
            "B" : "Intent",
            "C" : "Message",
            "D" : "CallBack"
        },
        "answer": "B"
    },{
    "questionId": 17,
    "question": "By using __________ attribute we can define the number of stars to display in RatingBar.",
    "options": {
        "A" : "android\\:numStars",
        "B" : "android\\:numberStars",
        "C" :  "android\\:noOfStars ",
        "D" : "android\\:totalNumberOfStars"
    },
    "answer": "A"
},{
    "questionId": 18,
    "question": "Can we call another activity using explicit intent?",
    "options": {
        "A" : "True",
        "B" : "False"
    },
    "answer": "A"
},{
    "questionId": 19,
    "question": "______________ folder contains XML files that describe the layout of the widgets (like buttons, text fields, Spinner, etc.) on the screens in your android application.",
    "options": {
        "A" : "XML",
        "B" : "layout",
        "C" : "res",
        "D" : "src"
    },
    "answer": "B"
},{
    "questionId": 20,
    "question": "]If EditText field is for password, then we need to specify the value of attribute _______ as “textPassword”.",
    "options": {
        "A" : "inputType",
        "B" : "DataType",
        "C" : "ispassword",
        "D" : "None Of This"
    },
    "answer": "D"
}
]
